Ben (00:03.322)
Hey, welcome to
another episode of The Circuit. I am Ben Bajarin.
Jay (00:08.45)
Greetings programs. I'm Jay Goldberg.
Ben (00:11.204)
Well, we've got some
very special guests. We are joined
by Mark Wade, CEO of Ayar Labs,
and Jesse Leiter, who is—you can give
your title, I think Head of Finance,
Ayar finance bro. But why don't you guys say
hi real quick, and then we'll jump into it.
Mark Wade (00:31.18)
Yeah, yeah. Hey everyone. My
name is Mark Wade. I'm the co-founder and CEO of
Ayar Labs. Ben and Jay, thanks for having us on.
Jesse Leiter (00:39.876)
Yeah, thanks, Jay and Ben. My
name is Jesse Leiter, VP of Capital Strategy and
Investor Relations. The role has changed; it had
a strategic finance element to it before, Ben,
so you're not completely off on that. But yeah,
we're really excited to be here. I think Jay and
I have been speaking for a little bit less than
a year now, and he'd mentioned the podcast. Ben,
I know you've been talking to Mark more recently,
so yeah, excited to be here speaking
to your audience and on your platform.
Ben (01:07.13)
Yeah, it's great to
have you guys. This is a very hot topic. I know
that since you guys are not a public company,
there are always people asking us, "Hey, what
are your thoughts on Ayar Labs? We're trying to
get more information." So I think this will be
super informative for our audience. My context
is—because you guys haven't heard me say this,
but Jay and I joke about this for a long time—The
Circuit is slowly becoming more of a networking
show. The irony of this is, back in the day,
we all covered networking, but it was relative
to telco and it was super boring. Like, "Great.
You've got more switches, sure fiber's great. This
is all interesting." When we started this podcast,
it was largely compute, looking at compute trends,
and then the network became this whole thing,
right? Interconnects and whatnot. So now we
spend so much more time talking about it, but
it's relevant because the interconnect is a wall.
It's a problem to solve. It's one of those big
hurdles to get over. In fact, GPUs and even memory
are scaling faster than the interconnect wall is,
right? So I think that's super interesting. At a
high level, as we start, Mark, why don't you just
give our audience, in case they aren't familiar
with you guys, the high-level pitch for Ayar Labs.
Mark Wade (02:29.719)
Yeah, so let me try to
start with a one or two-sentence framing, which
is that large-scale AI data centers are limited
in their revenue scaling by the performance
of the interconnect in their compute systems.
That's a claim that says, hey, if we want a path
to continuing to scale AI data center revenues,
to continue to grow the supply of token
throughput, to improve the tokens per
second per dollar per watt on these tokenomics,
while simultaneously improving the performance of
these frontier leading-edge AI models,
their architectures, and reasoning models,
we have to improve the interconnect. So that's
the high-level motivation, which is that we view
solving this interconnect bottleneck as one of the
core major hardware-level bottlenecks that needs
to be solved to keep the AI roadmaps running.
Now if we double-click into that a little bit,
the bottlenecks are coming from these electrical
interconnects that exist in the so-called scale-up
fabric. The scale-up fabric connects a number
of GPUs and AI accelerators together. You've got
this issue in electrical interconnects where the
faster you want to go—the more data you want to
send between these GPUs and accelerators—the
shorter distance you can go. We call that the
bandwidth-distance trade-off. The only way we
know how to solve this from first principles,
from the ground up, is to swap over to optical
connectivity. That's where we say we've got to get
a new generation of deeply integrated, CMOS-scale
optical connectivity into the scale-up fabric,
solve this bottleneck from the ground up where
the real physics problem is happening, and then
we enter the promised land beyond. So that's the
quick snapshot of what Ayar Labs is trying to do.
Jay (04:42.882)
So I've covered optical for a long time,
all through the telecom ups and downs and ups and
more downs. If you asked me to do word association
with the idea of optical networking, the one word
that comes to mind first is "pain." This stuff is
hard to do. It's tripped up many people over the
years again and again. Why is optical so hard?
Mark Wade (05:09.462)
Yeah. I do think if
you want to try to build things in this
area, you have to be a bit masochistic.
You have to enjoy the process of pain and
suffering and solving hard, complex problems.
I'd say with optical devices and optical
solutions, part of the challenge is that to really
get a full end-to-end electronic and photonic
solution to work, you're talking about the
combination of multiple domains of technology and
expertise. In previous paradigms in the industry,
like in telecommunications, you had specialization
in those different domains. You'd have entire
companies that just provided a single laser.
Or you had entire companies that provided the
DSP engines or parts of the electrical circuits
that connect to the optical devices. And then
you had entire companies that just built the
optical devices. I think part of the challenge
is that each of these domains is difficult, and
you've got to put them all together in a way that
can actually build a product and work end-to-end.
There's material science involved, device design,
and manufacturing back-end challenges.
It's layers upon layers of deep, technical,
difficult problems. Optics layers into anything
that's difficult in CMOS and high-performance
electronics, and then you layer optics on top of
that with different supply chains and different
material and device requirements. There are just
a lot of difficult problems there. So you'll find,
if you come to a company like ours or
other photonics and optics companies,
it's a very high density of PhDs, of people
with physics, electrical engineering,
and mechanical engineering backgrounds.
So I think that's just the truth of it.
Jay (07:30.818)
So why now? What's changed
that makes this buildable today when it wasn't,
say, five years ago, or before you started?
Mark Wade (07:39.469)
Well, let me draw from a little bit of
what I just talked about. One thing we recognized
early on—and I didn't touch on it in the intro—is
that myself and my co-founders have been working
on this for fifteen years, first starting mostly
at MIT and Berkeley. We started Ayar Labs coming
out of MIT in 2015 while we were still students.
I also like to say all I've done in my adult
life is try to get this technology to work.
Ben (08:09.208)
Mm-hmm.
Mark Wade (08:09.602)
Yeah, we're fully committed
and all in on it. But let's talk about the "why
now" and what had to happen to enable things.
I want to go back to asking, how did it used to
look? I just described these telecommunications
products and solutions. You have to look at it
by asking what problem they were solving in the
marketplace, what was the value of that problem,
and what was the right configuration of companies,
supply chains, and value stacks to
solve that problem. The reality was
the volumes in datacom—actually, the volumes in
telecom were fairly small. So you had bespoke,
relatively small, and niche supply chains
that were able to deliver to them. Datacom
was supposedly this huge market that was much
bigger than the optics community was ever exposed
to. Now that we're talking about going from what
was traditional datacom all the way into optical
connectivity coming out of GPUs, AI accelerators,
optically connected memory, and scale-up switches,
this is a 10 to 100x larger volume than the
datacom market was serving. The "why now"
is about saying we needed a market application
whose high-value revenue was actually gated by
connectivity—chip-to-chip connectivity, rack-scale
connectivity, and rack-to-rack connectivity.
The reality is that before large-scale AI
exploded onto the scene, there just wasn't a
market application large enough with high enough
value revenue gated by connectivity. So now we
have that. The awareness of that started a few
years ago. For a lot of people, ChatGPT getting
released was the wake-up call in our industry
because everyone very quickly understood how the
core computation of these applications scales. A
lot of the work that we and others had been doing
showed how connectivity was going to gate and
be a critical limiter to building large-scale
distributed computing systems. We've been working
on that since 2010 and before, so we had all the
core technological ideas from the ground up in
place, and we'd made a lot of progress. But we
needed the spark of a market application that
made large-scale distributed computing highly
valuable. That's what releasing ChatGPT did.
Now we could talk more about it, saying, "Hey,
ChatGPT came out a few years ago, so why hasn't
Ayar Labs IPO'd and why isn't CPO everywhere?"
I'm sure we'll dig into that next. But I would
say the tier-one volume ecosystem finally got
fully interested leading up to the ChatGPT
release and the year after. The reality is,
the tier-one high-volume advanced semiconductor
ecosystem can't pivot on a dime, right?
Ben (11:46.736)
And maybe before we get into some of the
timing of these things, maybe just talk a little
bit about the manufacturing challenges. We hear
this a lot. I know you've got to be deep in the
weeds, you've got to be in foundries to do this,
but everybody keeps telling me it's just really
hard. The wafer side is hard, all of it. So I'd
love just brief color. Help us understand why the
manufacturing side of this is also so difficult.
Mark Wade (12:14.774)
Yeah, and I think we are seeing
people go through their own educational process,
trying to understand what the complexities around
building photonics really are, especially the way
we're trying to build them now for co-packaged
optics and even other form factors. Let me
try to come at it from a few different angles,
because everyone is coming from their own
understanding and you have to map it to a
few things. One of the first things to realize
is that we say we're building an optical engine.
Our optical engine is a combination of a
leading-edge advanced node electrical IC
(EIC). Right now we build in the TSMC COUPE
process, where the EIC is a three-nanometer
IC with hundreds of millions of transistors. So
you should think of this as photonics adding a
new high-performing, leading-edge advanced
capability to leading-edge CMOS nodes and
leading-edge advanced packages. The first
thing to realize is that people generally know
that leading-edge CMOS is hard and advanced
packaging is hard. People know about CoWoS,
the supply chain shortages, and the challenges
in getting these large-package, multi-die
AI accelerators manufactured and produced. You
should just bootstrap into that understanding
that a large multi-die package AI accelerator
is a difficult thing to manufacture and
build even without optics, okay? So now we're
going to say I'm going to take this large
leading-edge substrate, multi-reticle advanced
package, and add an optical engine. The optical
engine is a combination of leading-edge EICs
and a new photonics wafer manufacturing process
flow. The new thing I have to do there is also
attach an optical connector to this package.
Mark Wade (14:36.29)
I think that's the easiest
way to see it, at least for people coming
from the understanding that multi-reticle,
large package size compute accelerators are
difficult to build. Now you're adding a new
advanced capability into that package. Difficult
on difficult makes it more difficult. So why is
everyone doing this? Why is everyone so motivated?
It's because we've really hit the physical limits
to escape the amount of bandwidth and the radix of
connectivity out of these large packages. You've
got multiple technologies within that package
that are fully pushed up against their physical
bounds. You need a new feature that can come in
and open up a new degree of freedom of scaling.
And that's just on the CMOS and large package
size. There are things to talk about on the
laser manufacturing side and the production
test architecture. How do we get photonics
bootstrapped into CMOS-scale, end-to-end wafer
testing and assembly testing? That's really where
the current crunch points and cycles of learning
are being accumulated and focused right now.
Ben (16:05.667)
Yeah. Let's get back to that in
a second. I want to talk a little bit about some
of the timing and different solutions out there.
I don't think we necessarily need a breakdown of
where each one fits, from LPO to CPO, though CPO
is interesting. But I am curious, as figuring
out the timing of this is really hard. We also
understand that everybody building infrastructure
is kind of taking their own approach to this. If
they mix and match interconnects, it could be
copper, PCIe, micro-LED, or optics—all these
things may exist in different implementations to
get over this wall. When you guys look at this
landscape, how do you see the interconnect
playing out? Do you think one solution
wins in the end and becomes dominant,
or do you think it might be a big mix
and match of all these things as guys
try to figure out their rack designs?
Mark Wade (17:13.334)
I'll tell you how I think about this.
In the last couple of years, from our largest
customers and even well-funded startup accelerator
communities, the demand for a solution that
makes optical connectivity exiting the package
look like something that can be high-volume
scaled through a CMOS-like manufacturing flow
is unquestioned. It allows customers to start
thinking of optical I/O within the context of
their foundry OSAT model of the world. Once we get
to that world, it simplifies a lot of the product
design, form factors, and configurations and
choices you have to make. So I do think there's
a trajectory as we get past this crunch in the
next three, four, or five years. When we land in
a world where optical connectivity is just viewed
as an advanced feature coming from a foundry,
that simplifies the world a lot for people. You
can get out of this chaotic land of, "Is it a
pluggable? Is it a board-integrated component?
What's the form factor? What's the physical
technology inside? What supply chain is delivering
it?" There are a lot of permutations you have to
manage to simply overcome the fact that you can't
get this from your CMOS foundry. So I think the
longer-term view—let's say 2030 and beyond—starts
to simplify and get easier. But in the short term,
when the reality is that these things are not
fully available in high-volume production today,
it forces everyone to scramble to find
their 2027 or 2028 stopgap solution.
Mark Wade (19:32.995)
That triggers a full exploration of the
solution space, which is a combination of which
technologies are close enough to solve my problem,
and what supply chains are supporting and
delivering them. You can have the greatest
technology in the world, but if you can't
ramp true volume production, it's not a
solution for customers trying to build high-volume
rack-scale architectures and deploy them on time.
Everyone's optimizing for their time to
the first token that generates revenue.
Ben (19:45.711)
Mm.
Mark Wade (20:01.896)
So yeah, I think in the
short term we're going to live through a chaotic,
turbulent set of technologies and form factors.
But in the longer term, we're going to land
this new generation of silicon photonics into a
TSMC-like foundry plus OSAT flow. Companies
like ours are focusing our efforts on building
the highest-performance chips in that
environment. We think once we prove
that it can be delivered at high-volume scale,
it simplifies a lot of the customer problem.
Jay (21:00.824)
Let me step aside for a second. What's
the nerdiest detail of your technology
that you just get excited about? That may be
obscure or super esoteric to other people?
Mark Wade (21:17.208)
Well, my academic training
was in physics and electrical engineering, and
I spent my graduate years working on the silicon
photonics device technologies that are now
underneath everything happening in co-packaged
optics and even things like NPO. I can still get
really excited about the core device technology,
and I designed a lot of those core devices in
my previous years. But what I've learned about
myself—and a lot of people coming from physics
think like this—is that I tend to get most
excited about trying to understand things from
the ground up. Whenever I run into something I
can't quite fully wrap my head around yet,
I spend most of my energy and excitement
in those areas. What that looks like for me today
is I'm having so much fun with all these coding
agent models that are out now—Claude Code, GPT-4,
etc. I'm spending time building a full end-to-end
digital twin manufacturing model of what this new
world of co-packaged optics, laser supply chain,
TSMC packaging, and all the test insertions
looks like. How do you build the right model
at the core of that? How do you implement it as
a directed acyclic graph so I can do lazy runtime
evaluation to keep track of all the details that
need tracking? I'm actually getting very excited
about it. The manufacturing is very complex, but
if you have visibility and see how it's all coming
together, there's a phenomenal opportunity to
optimize details that we think will be critical
to getting a volume production solution. What do
I mean by details? Depending on my business model
and exactly how the materials are yielding coming
out of the core manufacturing steps, what's my
optimal test policy across five test insertions?
Which one makes sense for me versus my customer?
There's a very rich set of interesting questions
that have non-obvious optimal solutions.
Strangely enough, that's what I'm spending
my nights and weekends on right now—burning
a lot of coding agent tokens to build a
digital twin model of all these things.
Ben (24:25.839)
Nice. All right,
so you guys have made a very specific
bet on a very specific solution. What are the
technical bets you guys are making as a company?
Jay (24:26.497)
Nice.
Mark Wade (24:54.978)
I'd actually say our
bet is broad and obvious, which is that you're
going to have optical connectivity coming out of
large-scale leading-edge advanced packages. To do
that, optical chips have to come out of CMOS-like
leading-edge foundries and supply chains. That's
really the core bet we've made as a company,
and the founding bet as well. There's going to
be a future where optics moves inside the compute
package and into the computing fabric. We used to
call it the memory semantic fabric. We built the
first-ever processor-to-DRAM optical interface
and published that in Nature back in 2015. So
the foundational bet was optics is going to go
into computing fabrics. If you want to deliver
something at that scale, compute products in
that space are built in leading-edge CMOS-like
supply chains. To us, that means a leading-edge
foundry like TSMC. That leads us into why we fully
focused on TSMC COUPE, and not just the foundry,
but foundry plus OSAT. How do you build this full
advanced package where a lot of these pieces
come together? To me, that's an obvious bet.
Everything you dive into in the technology weeds
starts from that insight. We could get into
micro-ring resonators, mux/demux filters, dense
wavelength division multiplexing on the laser
side, and why we chose external light sources.
But those details came from a higher-level bet.
Mark Wade (27:15.938)
And the higher-level bet
was we have to make photonics look like
CMOS leading-edge scale manufacturing.
Ben (27:22.125)
That's a good point. I hear whispers
from folks concerned that TSMC is immature
in this space. You'll hear about Tower and
GlobalFoundries, making it sound like others are
further along. You're making a big bet on this,
working with TSMC in-house and everything under
one roof with your customers. Give us some color
on your confidence level that TSMC is the right
bet and that they're on a path moving forward.
Mark Wade (28:06.316)
Let me start with a couple
of general statements, and then I'll get specific
on TSMC COUPE. We've got lots of wafers flowing
out of the fab right now, so I think we're in a
good position to make comments. It depends on your
mental model of how hard things make progress.
Hard things make progress by always going through
a phase of difficulty. If you ask, "Are you guys
having challenges getting things working?" Yes.
I tell our company we have to assume we're going
to go from very difficult to figuring it all out,
to fully in production. That's true
not just for the CMOS foundry side,
but for almost every single thing.
Jay (28:41.536)
Yeah.
Mark Wade (29:03.898)
I know where some of
this commentary comes from because a lot of
people in the finance world are trying to
track things on a weekly or monthly basis, but in
technology, we make progress quarterly or yearly.
So there's a mismatch in the language we use
to describe these things. Let me go to TSMC
COUPE. First, Ayar Labs is a fabless company,
so we hope that in ten or twenty years, we have
a rich set of foundry solutions to develop
products in. A lot of times, people make these
comments comparing one foundry's photonics chip
to another's. But a photonics chip is nowhere near
the final product form factor. The final product
looks like a full advanced leading-edge package.
Jay (30:14.338)
Mm.
Mark Wade (30:25.016)
My optical engine needs a very high-performing
advanced CMOS EIC. It needs to be 3D integrated
and advanced packaged with a photonics chip to
become a TSMC COUPE wafer. It then needs to go
through a scalable post-foundry OSAT ecosystem
and integrate into the most advanced packages
in the world. Only after that can you say you
have a real path to a differentiated product in
a market that can consume it at volume scale.
That is where we've chosen to make our bet. Can
you use a photonics chip from another foundry
to build a pluggable transceiver or NPO modules?
Yes, I think plenty of photonics foundries will
successfully supply into those form factors.
But to say the opportunity is in scale-up
and attaching into a compute fabric, GPU, AI
accelerator, or optically connected memory—we're
members of the NVIDIA ecosystem, so attaching
to NVLink and NVSwitch takes a different set of
requirements. We define our success
metric by how you build a product,
how you build a supply chain, and what
ecosystem will successfully deliver.
TSMC has been a phenomenal partner. We've been
working in TSMC COUPE for approaching four years
now. We know how to build electronic and photonic
solutions, and TSMC is the number one foundry in
the world. They know how to build high-volume,
high-quality, wafer-scale technologies. From a
wafer foundry process perspective, silicon
photonics just isn't that hard to do.
Mark Wade (32:51.51)
You need high-quality silicon
waveguides, materials like silicon nitride, and
a good photodetector material; we and almost
everyone else use germanium for detectors.
You need a good way to get fibers connected
to get the light onto and off the chip,
which ends up being the most challenging
part. But the rest of what you need looks like
advanced node CMOS and advanced packaging. We
just view photonics as a critical piece
of what we're building—it's necessary
for phenomenal performance, but nowhere
near sufficient for the full solution.
Jay (33:48.365)
What are the biggest
hurdles to adoption that you're hearing from
customers? I know there are technical challenges,
but looking at the customer side, what
is preventing them from adopting this?
Mark Wade (34:07.852)
I tend to break the
customer sets into a few different classes,
which also explains our strategic investor
relationships. We were very intentional
in building our strategic investors and
development partners because it reflects
how we needed to work with the industry.
You have to work very closely with the high-volume
supply chain that's going to scale this. We have
multiple rounds of equity investment from TSMC
and other go-to-market partners. We did the
thought experiment all the way out to rack-scale
infrastructure. We recently announced that Wiwynn
is one of our strategic investors. We also
worked closely with those who would experience
the highest value proposition of co-packaged
optics—the ones building GPUs and AI accelerators.
On our cap table, we've got multiple rounds
of investment from NVIDIA, AMD, and Intel.
That anchors the collection of leading-edge GPU
customers and foundry supply chain partners.
Mark Wade (36:34.476)
The leading guys burn down the new technology
risk. They need to successfully deploy it. Beyond
that, everyone building their SOCs through ASIC
service partnerships needs to view it as something
with nearly zero risk. That's why we built very
close strategic relationships with MediaTek,
Alchip, and GUC. It builds the go-to-market
partnerships so hyperscaler accelerator products
and even startups can get access to leveraging the
Ayar Labs optical engine through an ASIC service
integration partner. I think we're going to see a
lot of exciting things from the leading-edge GPU
guys in 2028 and 2029. Then in 2029 through 2031,
you'll see it proliferate to the rest of the
accelerator community. By the time they bring
it in, it needs to be essentially zero risk,
treated just like how they integrate HBM.
Ben (38:05.845)
That's a good point. Jesse, I want to throw this
question to you. Mark mentioned your strategic
investors. You've taken multiple rounds. We were
talking about being strategic with your cap table,
which obviously matters. Can you talk a little
bit about that, and any thoughts on an IPO?
Jay (38:31.287)
Yeah.
Jesse Leiter (38:38.706)
Sure, Ben. For an early-stage deep tech startup,
Silicon Valley VCs haven't been active in this
space for many years. Early on, you try to convert
deep tech funds who get the business model and are
willing to take that risk on a pre-revenue asset.
Simultaneously, as Mark mentioned, you
build ecosystem development partners that
are strategic to commercial paths over time to
figure out the volume scale production story.
It takes many years of deep integration.
We were shipping a two-terabit chiplet,
a four-terabit chiplet, and eventually
an eight-terabit chiplet to customers.
Getting into their R&D labs and seeing an
end-to-end solution that works allowed us
to show proof points to institutional investors,
who are really going to fund the path forward.
Jesse Leiter (40:43.026)
In our Series D, it was
very unique in that we had strategic
participation from NVIDIA, AMD, Intel,
and TSMC, but we also brought in two high-quality
institutional investors that led the round.
We set a path with a valuation that we thought was
very sensible. We didn't want to have to grow into
a very high valuation because we had execution
risk ahead of us, so we wanted to be mindful
of building the right cap table. Fast forward 12
months, and you have a CPO switch roadmap laid out
by Jensen at GTC. Sell-side analysts started
writing actively on CPO for the first time.
When they start seeing this getting deployed into
scale-out roadmaps, you get a lot of questions
about the technology and scaling path. We were
able to get in front of high-quality investors and
convert an exciting Series E round earlier
this year, led by a large long-only fund,
Neuberger Berman. We also had participation from
sovereign wealth funds like QIA in the Middle East
and GIC in Singapore, and a number of crossover
investors valuable for the IPO path, like Sequoia,
Insight Partners, and ARC. We're integrated
into the backend channel alongside MediaTek
and Alchip to deliver CPO at scale to multiple
players. To your question on the path forward,
we want to be strategic about who will be there
for us at the IPO. We put out a press release last
week on the Wiwynn strategic investment,
which topped our capital on the balance
sheet to $650 million. There was also press
from Reuters about a secondary transaction
that allowed us to bring in more high-quality
institutional investors for the path forward.
Mark Wade (42:38.914)
The only thing I'd add is,
if you do the spreadsheet math on the market
opportunity, unit volumes, and reasonable
ASP targets, optics going into this scale-up
opportunity is a tens-of-billions to approaching a
hundred-billion-dollar market size. It's not hard
to motivate the financial math. We view our job as
getting the end-to-end supply chain delivering
to that volume. The intercept timeline being
around 2028 or 2029 creates a very exciting
path for how we would think about an IPO.
Jay (43:40.547)
I've worked on a
few dozen IPOs over the years, and
I see this phenomenon a lot where
technical founders encounter the street for the
first time, and the questions they ask aren't
necessarily top of mind for you. What's a question
you wish investors asked you, but never do?
Mark Wade (44:10.86)
It's interesting, Jay. I have to give credit
to Jesse for helping with this. The Silicon Valley
world abandoned this space for a long time, so the
financial capital came from public and crossover
investors. I've had to cut my teeth on building
my skill set to see how they think, what they're
really measuring, and how they view the business.
Mark Wade (45:10.24)
We had to find enough of
those investors in Series D and Series E who were
willing to dive deep into the technology. However,
if we execute, my IPO roadshow should be much
simpler. We'll be shifting from explaining
lots of details on technology to speaking
the language of financial metrics, with
high visibility into our revenue ramp. Because the
relationship is so close with leading customers,
you have high visibility and supply commitments
into what the ramp looks like. If we do our job
well at Ayar Labs, by the time we're on an IPO
roadshow, we'll talk about technology enough to
prove we have a robust, defensible core, and then
we'll speak the language of how you value this in
the public markets. But to answer your question,
at a dinner Jesse took me to earlier this week
with Jefferies, for the first time in the US, I
was asked about test equipment vendors, probers,
and test insertions. It's been interesting
over the last six to nine months to see
public investors really get into the weeds of the
world I live in. It makes the dinners more fun
and interesting for me, even though I don't
get to eat any of the lobster in front of me.
Jesse Leiter (47:38.504)
I would also add that some of these investors
have been very transparent. They are in it for the
long game. They want to hear what we're saying,
what we're doing, what we are able to execute on,
and see how that aligns with our timelines over
time. It builds trust with the company and the
management team so that they are at the IPO to
support us. It's about building a relationship
that is well aligned with that IPO timeframe.
Ben (48:24.335)
This is fascinating, guys.
It's interesting times because the race is really
to build compute domains where giant clusters
function as one computer network together. We're
so far away from that really happening, which
boggles my mind because the models necessitate
that. Everybody's making trade-offs right now
because we don't have that yet, which shows how
early we are in this process. As you mentioned,
the space you guys play in is estimated between
30 and 50 billion dollars by 2030, which is
going to scale quickly. We really appreciate the
conversation and your time coming on The Circuit.
Mark Wade (49:48.448)
Thanks. This was a
great discussion. By the way, we
didn't even talk about lasers,
so that could be a future episode because
that's the other big part of this story.
Jay (49:53.367)
Yeah.
Ben (49:53.987)
We will talk about
lasers at a future time for sure. We'll
do a whole segment on lasers with you.
Jesse Leiter (50:02.439)
Very good.
Mark Wade (50:02.769)
Okay, good. I'll look forward to it.
Jesse Leiter (50:05.106)
Thank you.
Ben (50:06.189)
Thanks for listening,
everybody. We appreciate your time and
we'll catch you next time on The Circuit.
Jay (50:11.224)
Thanks for listening, everybody.